A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Secretary and General Counsel, Grant Records, Organizational Grants FA1510
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Recommended Grant Action Forms and Affirmative Action Statements, 1
  - South East Alabama Self-Help Association (SEASHA), 1974-1984 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    1982 January - Continued general support to a CDC operating in 12 rural counties in Alabama
    1978 April - Continued general support to a CDC operating in 12 rural counties in Alabama
    1977 February - This investment will enable SEASHA to expand its rural land planning and development program
    1975 December - Continued general support to a CDC operating in 12 rural counties in Alabama
    1982 April - Continued general support to a CDC operating in 12 rural counties in Alabama
    1974 January - Continued general support to a CDC operating in 12 rural counties in Alabama
  - Simmons College, 1977 August (Box 3, Folder 126)
    Support to Establish a Summer Program in Case Teaching
  - Southeast Asian Mutual Assistance - Associations Coalition, Inc., 1985 April (Box 3, Folder 127)
    Partial core support for the Southeast Asian Mutual Assistance Associations Coalition
  - Southeast Bronx Community Organization, 1980 April (Box 3, Folder 128)
    To mount a housing-related human service program
  - Southeast Development, Inc., 1975-1986 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    1986 February - 760-0084 Support of central and project administration
    1984 August - Support for a program of public education and training activities on United States-Latin American Relations
    1982 January - Support of central and project administration in a white ethnic community development corporation
    1979 November - Support of central and project administration in a white ethnic community development corporation
    1977 October - Support of central and project administration in a white ethnic community development corporation
    1976 September - Partial support for a prepaid housing maintenance repair service to complement neighborhood conservation efforts
    1975 November - Support of central and project administration in a white ethnic community development corporation
    1975 May - Loan to enable SECO to undertake an experimental land banking and neighborhood revitalization program
  - Southeast Women's Employment Coalition, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    1986 May - Support for Economic Research and Education Program, Supplement No. 1
    1985 August - Partial support for the Women't Opportunity in Road Construction Project, Supplement No. 1
    1984 March - Support for Economic Research and Education Program
    1983 May - Partial support for the Women't Opportunity in Road Construction Project, a program designed to enhance employment opportunities for women in federally-supported road construction in the Southeast
  - Southern Agriculture Swine Corporation (Southern Agriculture Corp), 1981 July (Box 3, Folder 131)
    Purchase of preferred stock of the Southern Agriculture Swine Corporation to enable it to lever an additional $2.7 million for the expansion of its existing swine farm operation
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1982 October (Box 3, Folder 132)
    Support for continuation of a program of technical assistance based on self-studies of accredited black colleges in the South
  - University of Southern California, 1974-1985 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    1984 January - Support of central and project administration in a white ethnic community development corporation
    1978 January - Planning grant for a 10 part dramatic series for public television, based on ethnicity and aging
    1974 December - Supplemental and terminal support of a study of tax and school finance problems in California (#740-0088)
  - Southern California Center for Law in the Public Interest, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    1975 February - #720-067A General Support
    1977 February - Contribution to the Center's capital fund drive
  - The Southern California Conference on International Studies, 1973 December (Box 3, Folder 135)
    General support
  - Southern California Ecumenical Council, 1986 February (Box 3, Folder 136)
    Partial support for a housing and integrated services project for Central American refugees
  - Southern Center for International Studies, Atlanta, 1982 December (Box 3, Folder 137)
    Study of the Employment Creation Capacity of the Egyptian Economy
  - Southern Coalition for Educational Equity, 1979-1986 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    1986 June - To support advocacy and intervention programs in inner-city middle-school mathematics
    1979 November - Partial support for project to improve effectiveness of women and minorities in positions of educational leadership in public schools
    1981 November - Support for a national coalitin of regional and local organizations working to increase the representation of women in administrative positions in elementary and secondary schools
  - Southern Cooperative Development Fund, Inc., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    This investment will enable SCDF to extend additional financing to low income cooperatives in the rural South
  - Southern Development Foundation, 1974-1985 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    1985 January - Project support for development of black church service delivery programs to benefit the disadvantaged
    1984 July - Partial support for a rural development program for low-income black farmers in the Southeast
    1982 April - Partial support for a rural development program for low-income black farmers in the Southeast
    1978 April - a rural development program for low-income black farmers in the Southeast
    1976 June - #730-0212 General support for a regional coordinating agency providing technical assistance and training to farming cooperatives in the rural south
    1975 March - #730-0212 General support for a regional coordinating agency providing technical assistance and training to farming cooperatives in the rural south
    1974 June - #730-0212 General support for a regional coordinating agency providing technical assistance and training to farming cooperatives of low income black farms in the rural south
    1977 April - #730-0212 General support for a regional coordinating agency providing technical assistance and training to farming cooperatives of low income black farms in the rural south
  - Southern Education Foundation, 1978-1985 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    1985 May - Supplemental support for desegregation research and monitoring activities
    1984 September - To support public policy research in minority access to higher education
    1983 June - To support research, monitoring and technical assistance in the desegregation of higher education
    1982 July - To support minority public policy research in education
    1981 May - To assist minority public policy research in education
    1980 February - To strengthen predominantly minority post-secondary institutions
    1980 February - Initiation of a service to distribute scripts of new plays
    1978 August - To help selected black colleges implement their ten year self-studies for re-accreditation
  - Southern Growth Policies Board, 1977 July (Box 4, Folder 142)
    Partial support of the Board's scholar-in-residence program
  - Southern Highland Handicraft Guild, 1979 August (Box 4, Folder 143)
    Support of development program of an organization serving Appalachian artisans
  - Southern Illinois University, 1980 March (Box 4, Folder 144)
    Partial support for design of policy alternatives to prevent significant deterioration of air quality in Illinois (Supplement to 785-0147)
  - Southern Prisoners' Defense Committee, 1981 March (Box 4, Folder 145)
    Partial support for a pilot project to develop materials to assist trial and appellate attorneys in nine Southern states in the preparation and presentation of capital cases
  - Southern Regional Council, Inc., 1973-1985 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    1985 December - For support of voting rights monitoring, technical assistance and educational outreach activities
    1984 August - Project support for educational outreach, monitoring, research and technical assistance activities pertaining to implementation of the Voting Rights Act of 1965, as amended
    1983 July - Project support for educational outreach, monitoring, research and technical assistance activities pertaining to implementation of the Voting Rights Act of 1965, as amended
    1978 February - Supplemental general support
    1981 March - Partial support for project to remove barriers to political participation by residents of predominantly black areas of the rural South
    1975 October - Supplemental general support
    1075 May - Supplemental support for a program of awards to individuals from Southeastern rural areas (Leadership Development Program 740-0258)
    1974 March - Support for monitoring of state and local government activity of selected programs in South Carolina under the direction of the South Carolina Council for Human Rights
    1974 March - Continued partial administrative support of a national Puerto Rican organization
    1974 February - Support for a Leadership Development Program, a program of awards to individuals from the southeasterm rural areas
    1973 November - Supplemental general support with specific emphasis on education, economic development, housing and health and, recoverable grant to help launch a region-wide magazine
    1975 September - Provides terminal support for the Task Force on Southern Rural Development
  - South Shore National Bank, 1977 February (Box 4, Folder 147)
    This investment will enable South Shore National Bank to continue its activities in inner-city rehabilitation and redevelopment
  - The Southwest Educational Development Corporation, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    1984 March - Terminal grant to support the Project AWARE/Women's Leadership Project in providing professional development for women education administrators in the Southwest
  - Southwest Research and Information Center, 1985 September (Box 4, Folder 149)
    Research and education to improve water use and management in Hispanic and Indian communities in northern New Mexico
  - Southwest Voter Registration Education Project, Inc., 1978-1985 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    1985 September - For general support of voter education, registration, research and legal programs
    1984 August - For general support of voter education, registration, research and legal programs
    1982 October - Continued general support of voter education, registration, research and legal program
    1981 October - Matching grant for continued general support of voter registration project
    1980 October - Matching grant for continued general support of voter registration project
    1979 October - Matching grant for continued general support of voter registration project
    1978 August - Matching grant for continued general support of voter registration project
  - Spanish Institute of International Affairs, 1981 September (Box 4, Folder 151)
    1) Partial support of a conference on the Maghreb countries
    2) Matching grant for general support
  - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, 1979-1986 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    1986 May - 1) Acquisition financing for a long term care facility; 2) Equity grant for acquistion and working capital
    1986 February - Administrative support for community development activities (730-0070)
    1983 February - Administrative support for community development activities (730-0070)
    1983 April - Administrative support for community development activities (730-0070)
    1979 October - Continued administrative support to three Chicano CDCs
    1975 October - Continued administrative support to three Chicano CDCs
    1974 November - $325,000 loan to enable SSUC to construct a Community Resources Center to provide office space for non-profit community service org.
  - Spanish Theatre Repertory Co., Ltd., 1986 March (Box 4, Folder 153)
    Support to three Hispanic theaters for institutional development
  - Spelman College (Atlanta, Georgia), 1983 August (Box 4, Folder 154)
    Support for projects to mainstream the new research on women into the core undergraduate curriculum of selected institutions across the country
  - Spring Hill College, 1986 June (Box 4, Folder 155)
    Projects in literacy and the liberal arts
  - Sports Foundation, Inc., 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    1981 November - Support for its Women's Progran
    1980 September - Renewed partial support for a youth program to work with community-based organizations in the South Bronx
    1980 June - To mount new program of sports, health and career counseling services for existin South Bronx organizations focused on youth
  - Government of Sri Lanka, 1984 January (Box 4, Folder 157)
    Support for training in field archaeology for Sri Lankan students and archaeologists at the Mantai excavation in Sri Lanka
  - Sri Nilakanteshwara Natyaseva Sangha (NINASAM) (India), 1986 March (Box 4, Folder 158)
    Support to strengthen the performing arts in rural Karnataka, Supplement No. 1
  - Srinivas Malliah Memorial Theater Crafts Trust, 1984 January (Box 4, Folder 159)
    Support for preservation of traditional theatre crafts in India
  - The Leland Stanford Junior University, 1974-1986 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    1986 June - 1) Partial support for a project on U.S.-Soviet efforts to develop a security regime 2) Partial support for an ongoing project on "Compliance and the Future of Arms Control"
    1985 September - To provide two fellowships per year for Third World and U.S. minority scholars at the Stanford Humanities Center
    1987 June - Support for the binational agriculture and rural development working group of the Stanford University U.S.-Mexico Project
    1984 August - 1) To provide support for an emeriti faculty development 2) To provide partial support for the Harper postdoctoral teaching program in the humanities and social sciences
    1981 September - Support for a faculty seminar on Public Policy Implications of Perceived Conflicts between Children's Interests and Feminists' Interests
    1981 September - Pilot education research training at the International Development Education Committee
    1981 August - Support for Analysis and Training on U.S.-Mexican Agricultural Relations
    1981 June - Support for study of the 1980 Cuban/Haitian exodus
    1981 January - Support to enable the Food Research Institute to undertake a commodity system study in Indonesia focusing principally on cassava, Supplement No. 1
    1979 December - Support for a Study of Chicanas in Post-Secondary Education
    1978 November - Matching endowment support for training and research on international security and arms control
    1978 September - Partial supplementary support of a longitudinal study to examine development processes in the differentiation of sex-typical behavioral patterns in young children (730-0185)
    1978 May - Support of research, training, and technical assistance regarding the uses and limits of school finance policy simulations
    1978 May - 1) Supplementary support of research and training program in education finance and governance (#74-201); 2) Study of demography of education work force in California and its implications for equity in education financing
    1976 June - Supplemental general support of selected public policy training and research programs
    1976 May - For financial aid to minority students at the graduate level in schools of journalism
    1975 July - Endowment grants for Asian studies
    1975 August - Research on the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe
    1974 February - Production of an annotated bibliography on women in Latin America
  - Stanford University, 1985 May (Box 4, Folder 161)
    General support for Inter-university Program on Latino Research
  - State Legislative Leaders Foundation, 1975 January (Box 4, Folder 162)
    Terminates support for the Program For Legislative Improvement
  - Staten Island Community College Association, Inc., 1975 November (Box 4, Folder 163)
    Partial support for the Cooperative Continuum, a program of reciprocal educational services involving all Staten Island schools and colleges
  - State University of Campinas (Brazil), 1982 August (Box 4, Folder 164)
    Support for graduate training and applied research in a newly-established Social Policy Studies Unit
  - Stiftung Wissenschaft und Politik, 1984 November (Box 4, Folder 165)
    Support for a study of the political rationale and morality of Western deterrence strategy
  - George C. Stoney Associates, Inc., 1974 April (Box 4, Folder 166)
    Matching funds to produce two documentary films covering the Vera Institute Supported Work Project and Vera's programs in criminal justice reform
  - Structured Employment/Economic Development Corporation (SEEDCO), 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    1986 June - A national program of grants and PRIs for development projects jointly sponsored by urban institutions and community development organizations
    1985 March - Support for a study of hospital and university complexes to identify community economic development opportunities
  - Martha Stuart Communications, Inc., 1983 August (Box 4, Folder 168)
    Partial support for the production and distribution of a videotape on people who have struggled with the abortion decision in various personal, social, or professional contexts
  - Studio Museum in Harlem, Inc., 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    1984 August - (1) Support for development of the Museum's collection and expansion of its fund-raising capabilty. (2) Partial support for an exhibition entitled "Tradition and Conflict: Images of a Turbulent Decade 1963-1973" on art of the civil rights period
    1979 December - Loan to finance renovation of new quarters
    1979 November - Fund-raising assistance
  - Studio Theatre School, 1976 January (Box 4, Folder 170)
    Support to improve and stabilize the financial position of selected performing arts organizations
  - Study Group on Mathematics of Porto Alegre (GEEMPA), 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    1985 September - Support for an experimental reading program for children from disadvantaged urban communities of Porto Alegre (Brazil), Supplement No. 1
    1983 May - Support for teacher training course and reading program for children from disadvantaged urban families
  - Suburban Action Institute, 1973-1980 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    1980 January - Partial support of a legal program and other activities to combat racial discrimination in housing
    1978 February - Program to promote equal opportunity in housing in the New York-New Jersey-Connecticut (77-201)
    1975 December - Monitoring of equal housing opportunity provisions of the federal community development program in the New York-New Jersey-Connecticut region (74-156)
    1973 December - Expansion of research and planning activities concerning housing need and environmental quality as factors in the development of suburban land
    1977 February - Programs to promote equal opportunity in housing and strengthen racially-mixed neighborhoods
  - Democratic Republic of the Sudan, Ministry of Irrigation, Hydraulic Research Station, 1985 May (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - Supported Work Corporation, 1976 July (Box 4, Folder 174)
    To provide partial support for the operation of a supported work program in Detroit
  - Swarthmore College, 1974 June (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - Syndicated Communications, Inc. (SYNCOM), 1976 March (Box 4, Folder 176)
    Investment in cumulative preferred stock to assist minority groups in acquiring and developing communications properties
  - Syracuse University, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 177)
    1978 April - A project to develop and implement a graduate research training component in the School of Education at Syracuse University
    1977 October - Support of curriculum development and related public policy training activities - Maxwell School of Citizenship and Public Affairs
    1974 March - To support research programs in productivity improvement at the state and local levels of government
    1974 January - Conference on public administration training at the Maxwell School of Citizenship and Public Affairs
    1973 November - Development of procedures for a performance assessment project for the Regents External High School Diploma
  - Tacolcy Economic Development Corporation, Inc. (Miami, Florida), 1985 February (Box 4, Folder 178)
    Continued support to strengthen the capacities of two CDCs undertaking housing and commercial revitalization projects
  - TAG Foundation, Ltd., 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 179)
    1979 November - Partial support of a series of performances by small and medium-sized dance companies
    1977 March - To assist the development of financial stability
    1976 February - Partial support for the presentation of modern dance companies under Dance Umbrella
  - Government of Tamil Nadu, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 180)
    Support for the integration of women into public sector extension systems in dairying, sericulture, small-scale industries, and agriculture
  - Tamil Nadu Agricultural University, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    1984 January - Support for integrated women's income-generation and development centers in rural areas of India
    1981 August - Development of rural social sciences at the University, Supplement No. 1
  - Task Force on Children Out of School, Inc., 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 182)
    1980 November - Support for demonstration of mediation techniques to juvenile cases involving status offenders and parent-child conflicts
    1977 March - Support for monitoring state government programs for children
    1975 April - Support for monitoring state government programs for children
  - Tata Institute of Social Sciences (India), 1982 April (Box 4, Folder 183)
    Support for development of women's studies
  - Tata Steel Rural Development Society, 1985 June (Box 4, Folder 184)
    Field trials for increasing equity in small-scale irrigation among landless tribal villagers
  - Tax Analysts and Advocates, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 185)
    1977 December - Supplemental general support of its monitoring, publishing and technical assistance activities in the area of tax policy (PA #760-0426)
    1976 June - General support of its monitoring, publishing and technical assistance activities in the area of tax policy
  - Paul Taylor Dance Company, 1978 January (Box 4, Folder 186)
    Affirmative action statement
  - Teachers and Writers Collaborative, 1976 June (Box 4, Folder 187)
    Affirmative Action Memo
  - Team for Justice, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 188)
    1974 August - Support for the planning of probation services demonstration project to be operated in Wayne County, Michigan
    1975 November - Support for the planning of probation services demonstration project to be operated in Wayne County, Michigan
    1977 February - Continued support for the planning of probation services demonstration project to be operated in Wayne County, Michigan
  - El Teatro Campesino, 1986 March (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - El Teatro de la Esperanza, 1986 March (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Technical Consultancy Services Organization of Karnataka, 1986 March (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Technical Development Corporation, 1983 January (Box 5, Folder 192)
    Technical assistance for five energy conservation programs in low-income neighborhoods and evaluations of their programs
  - Technoserve, Inc., 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    1986 January - Support for a community enterprise promotion project and a feasibility study for establishing a tea pickers association
    1985 July - Support for a needs assessment and pilot demonstration project for improved irrigation management in Peru
  - Telecommunications Cooperative Network, 1984 September (Box 5, Folder 194)